# **Ellen Houghton**

Trainee Level Junior Software Developer based in Central London, UK

I live in Westminster, London, W2

ellen.a.ash@gmail.com

annwyl21.github.io/ docker hub - annwyl21

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I made a bold decision to retrain in tech during the pandemic, self-studying HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python through Codecademy and the 'Get into Tech for Women' evening class. My healthcare background offers a distinct analytical lens, having previously delved into statistical software.

Now, I'm developing this with my growing coding passion. Currently enrolled in JustIT's Digital Skills Bootcamp, I'm refining my skills with Docker and GitHub for project management.

My goal is to be a Junior Developer in a thriving team. I actively engage in London's tech scene, attending meetups like ChatGPT Plugins and PyData, and participating in the Ladies of Code's TDD Club. I share these experiences on LinkedIn.

# GITHUB PROJECTS annwyl21.github.io/

# JavaScript, local Storage, html, css, debugging BrewQueue - To Do List

An order management system created using JavaScript. I successfully debugged critical issues, including an off-by-1 error and unpredictable card creation anomalies, using browser debugging tools to pinpoint a variable declaration oversight that JavaScript gracefully handled without explicit error, a contrast to typical Python behaviour.

# **Python Coding, problem solving and TDD (Pytest, Pextract)**Yahtzee - *Game written using test driven development*

I developed my yahtzee game following the principles of TDD that I have been learning in my weekly coding club with Ladies of Code. I have evidenced my progress with screenshots and github commit history.

# SQL (PostGreSQL), AI Prompt Engineering, Flask, Python

My app logs medical symptoms in a PostgreSQL database, sends a request prefixed with my meta prompt to the text-davinci-003 AI model, which returns a concise symptom summary, displayed alongside a symptom scatterplot, detailing date & number of symptoms and a pain measure.

# **RestAPI** Azure Cognitive Services API — A flask translation service

I connected to an Azure Cognitive services API from and followed a Microsoft tutorial to build my own translation service. I also have my **debt comparison calculator** in my **docker repository** and a weather **data visualisation** project.

#### **SKILLS**

# **Programming:**

Python

JavaScript, Regex

HTML, CSS

SQL

# Version Control & Containerisation:

Git, Docker

Git Bash

Ubuntu

Github, Github Workflow

Docker hub

# **Database Management:**

MySql

PostgreSQL

# Frameworks & Libraries:

Pytest, Pextract

Jest

Flask, Bootstrap

Matplotlib

Pandas, Numpy

NLTK, BS4

# IDE's:

**VSCode** 

Pycharm

Jupyter Notebook

# API's & AI Engineering:

Postman

Azure Cognitive API

AI Prompt Engineering

# **RECENT STUDY to complete Career Relaunch into Tech**

# Just IT Bootcamp 2023

July 2023 - September 2023

- 12-weeks
- daily
- Individual projects targeting fundamentals of web and software development

# Get into Tech Course 2023

January 2023 - April 2023

- 15-weeks
- weekly evening classes
- Team Projects targeting soft skills and collaboration on github

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Career Break

March 2009 - PRESENT

• cultivated skills in time management, organisation and coordination

# NHS, London — Speech & Language Therapist

September 2005 - March 2009

- successfully managed a caseload of 200+ children with therapy needs, ensuring timely and effective care
- led training sessions for 30+ school staff, imparting essential skills for managing children with special communication needs in classrooms
- worked for 2 central London healthcare trusts, across clinics, hospitals and primary schools
- worked directly with patients, clinicians and parents
- as part of a multidisciplinary care team, I collaboratively reviewed and determined care approaches for children, prioritising their unique needs ensuring the best possible outcome for each child

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# NHS, London — Speech & Language Therapy Assistant

August 2002 - August 2003

# **Reed**, London — Administrative Temp

March 2002 - August 2002

# **Insightful**, Berkshire — Distributor Sales and Marketing

December 1999 - February 2002

#### **CERTIFICATES**

**Agile Fundamentals** Jan 2023

**Cloud Computing** Jan 2023

JavaScript for Beginners Jan 2023

IT Security Fundamentals Jan 2023

**Python for Beginners** Feb 2023

Linux Command Line Feb 2023

#### **CODECADEMY CERTIFICATES**

How to clean data with python Feb 2022

Getting started with natural language processing Jan 2022

Visualise data with python Jan 2022

Learn python 3, Dec 2021

#### **EDUCATION**

PG Dip with Merit Speech & Language Therapy

2005

City University, London

# BSc Psychology

1997

Greenwich University, London